Inside everyone is a frontier waiting to be discovered.
Dances with Wolves is a adventure, drama, western
film directed by Kevin Costner.
Wounded Civil War soldier John Dunbar tries to commit
suicide—and becomes a hero instead.
As a reward, he's assigned to his dream post, a remote junction on the Western
frontier, and soon makes unlikely friends with the local Sioux tribe.
Lieutenant Dunbar, played by Kevin Costner.
Stands With A Fist, played by Mary McDonnell.
Kicking Bird, played by Graham Greene.
Wind In His Hair, played by Rodney A. Grant.
Ten Bears, played by Floyd "Red Crow" Westerman.
Black Shawl, played by Tantoo Cardinal.
Dances With Wolves is a 1990 American epic revisionist Western film starring,
directed, and produced by Kevin Costner in his feature directorial debut.
It is a film adaptation of the 1988 novel Dances With Wolves, by Michael
Blake, that tells the story of Union army Lieutenant John J.
Dunbar (Costner), who travels to the American frontier to find a
military post and who meets a group of Lakota.
Costner developed the film with an initial budget of $15 million.
Much of the dialogue is spoken in Lakota with English subtitles.
It was shot from July to November 1989 in South Dakota and Wyoming, and translated by Doris
Leader Charge, of the Lakota Studies department at Sinte Gleska University.
The film earned favorable reviews from critics and audiences, who praised Costner's directing,
the performances, screenplay, score, cinematography, and production values.
It was a box office hit, grossing $424.2 million worldwide, making it the
fourth-highest-grossing film of 1990, and is the highest-grossing film for Orion Pictures.
The film was nominated for 12 awards at the 63rd Academy Awards and won 7, including Best Picture, Best Director for Costner,
Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Film Editing, Best Cinematography, Best Original Score, and Best Sound Mixing.
The film also won the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Drama.
It is one of only four Westerns to win the Oscar for Best Picture, the other three being
Cimarron (1931),  Unforgiven (1992), and No Country for Old Men (2007).
It is credited as a leading influence for the revitalization of
the Western genre of filmmaking in Hollywood.
In 2007, Dances With Wolves was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by
the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of friendship, mutiny,
countryside, based on novel or book, unsociability.
The tone is emotional and intense.